-Hurry up -Hurry this way...
-서둘러 -이쪽으로 서둘러 ‥
I saw her, hurry up
그녀를 봤어, 서둘러
fast and fast chase
빠르고 빠른 추격
-This way... -Hurry and chase after him quickly.
-이쪽으로 ‥ - 서둘러 빨리 쫓아가라
-This way -Yes.
-이쪽으로 -네
- Stop and continue - Yes.
- 그만하고 계속하세요 - 예
Stop
멈추다
Come on, go on, hurry up
어서, 계속해, 서둘러
I can't catch it
잡을 수 없어
I can never go back like this
이대로는 절대 되돌릴 수 없어
Brothers and sisters, where are you going?
형제 여러분, 어디로 가시나요?
- Yes - Go here.
- 네 - 여기로 가세요
- Yeah - the rest follow me.
- 응 - 나머지는 날 따라와
fast‥
빠른‥
this way
이 방법
Let me go, I want to go back to the castle, let me go
놔줘 황성으로 돌아가고 싶어 놔줘
I am Zhongzhai's eldest son
나는 Zhongzhai의 장남입니다
How dare you catch me?
어떻게 감히 나를 잡을 수 있나요?
Let me go ‥
날 놔줘 ‥
How dare you say that I am Zhongzhai’s eldest wife?
감히 내가 중자이의 맏부인이라니
i am a big girl
나는 큰 여자입니다
I want to go back to the imperial castle
황성으로 돌아가고 싶다
Mrs. Hua is really cold-blooded and ruthless.
Hua 부인은 정말 냉혈하고 무자비합니다
You may ignore your own relatives.
자신의 친척을 무시할 수도 있습니다.
daughter
딸
impossible‥
불가능한‥
No way, this is not my brother.
말도 안돼, 이건 내 동생이 아니야
this is not my mom
이 사람은 우리 엄마가 아니야
I don't recognize it, no...
인식하지 못해요, 아니......
Dare to help exiles escape.
감히 망명자들의 탈북을 도우십시오.
20 sticks is considered a small amount of punishment.
막대기 20개는 적은 양의 처벌로 간주됩니다.
After all, he is still spoiled
결국, 그는 여전히 버릇이 없습니다
Thin skin and tender meat
얇은 껍질과 부드러운 고기
I didn't pass this either
이것도 통과하지 못했어
dare ‥
감히 ‥
What are you shouting?
당신은 무엇을 외치고 있습니까?
When the Hua family planned to force Director Mu to death.
Hua 가족이 Mu 감독을 강제로 죽음에 이르게 하려고 계획했을 때
I should have expected this day to come
오늘이 올 거라고 예상했어야 했는데
you deserve it
당신은 그럴 자격이 있어요
Wait a minute, you're almost there too.
잠깐만요, 너도 거의 다 왔어
you should have died a long time ago
당신은 오래전에 죽었어야 했어요
When you do these evil things
너희가 이런 악한 일을 행할 때
Have you ever thought about today?
오늘에 대해 생각해 본 적 있나요?
natural
당연한
- Yes - you deserve it.
- 네 - 당신은 그럴 자격이 있어요
-Retaliation -Yes
-보복 -예
deserve it
그럴만 한 자격이
why?
왜?
Why does this happen?
왜 이런 일이 발생합니까?
I deliberately plotted against many people.
나는 의도적으로 많은 사람들을 상대로 음모를 꾸몄습니다.
How did this happen?
어쩌다가 이렇게 됐지?
It's my fault?
내 잘못이야?
If I had a chance to do it again in my life
인생에서 다시 할 기회가 있다면
Are you going to make a change?
변화를 주실 건가요?
I can do it
저 할 수 있어요
girl‥
소녀‥
miss… … What's going on, girl?
아가씨……무슨 일이야, 아가씨?
-Let me go, let me go... -Let my girl go
-놔줘, 놔줘‥ - 우리 여자를 놔줘
-Woman- Fuck you.
-여자 - 엿 먹어라
- Let go, let go - Go
- 놔, 놔 ​​- 가
magistrate
치안 지
Second daughter... No, eldest sister
둘째딸‥아니요, 맏언니
Your uncle will be here in a moment.
잠시 후에 삼촌이 여기 오실 거예요.
You can't fall asleep
잠들면 안 돼
Now she is married to Zhongzhai.
이제 그녀는 Zhongzhai와 결혼했습니다.
Not as comfortable as a Chinese restaurant
중국집만큼 편하진 않아요
Madam Hua had warned her slave repeatedly before.
Hua 부인은 이전에도 자신의 노예에게 반복적으로 경고했습니다.
honeymoon night
신혼 여행 밤
Marry Zhongzai
중자이와 결혼하다
Didn’t this happen two years ago?
2년 전에 이런 일이 있지 않았나요?
Please come… please
오세요…제발
Drink wine‥
와인을 마시다‥
Dear uncle...
친애하는 삼촌 ‥
- Let's have a drink - Let's go.
- 한잔 하자 - 가자
- Let's drink together
- 같이 마시자
Have you discovered this happy day?
이 행복한 날을 발견하셨나요?
Why does your uncle feel unhappy?
삼촌이 행복하지 않다고 느끼는 이유는 무엇입니까?
How could I not be happy?
내가 어떻게 행복하지 않을 수 있겠는가?
Uncle, I have always been serious about words.
삼촌, 저는 항상 말에 대해 진지했습니다.
- Say it again - Uncle.
- 다시 말해 보세요 - 삼촌
second girl in chinese family
중국 가족의 두 번째 소녀
Music, chess, calligraphy, and paintings are all unique.
음악, 체스, 서예, 그림 모두 독특합니다.
Her father belongs to the Zhong family.
그녀의 아버지는 종 가문에 속한다.
Both people, regardless of their family background or appearance
두 사람 모두 집안 배경이나 외모에 상관없이
Everyone looks good together
다들 잘 어울리네요
-Uncle, let’s toast too-
-삼촌, 나도 건배하자 -
- Come... - Please.
- 오세요 ‥ - 부탁해요
please
제발
－Okay, let’s eat‥ －Okay‥
－알았어, 밥 먹자‥ － 알았어‥
what's the problem?
뭐가 문제 야?
girl?
소녀?
Is today the day Jong Ye-ran and I are getting married?
오늘이 종예란과 제가 결혼하는 날인가요?
yes… yes
예… 예
Where are my mother and my brother?
내 어머니와 내 동생은 어디에 있나요?
At this time, his wife and eldest son
이때 부인과 큰 아들이
I am planning to hold a banquet with Du Guan at the Chinese residence.
나는 중국인 거주지에서 두관과 함께 연회를 열 예정이다.
Is my dad still alive?
우리 아빠는 아직 살아 계시나요?
Second woman, what are you talking about?
둘째 여자야, 무슨 소리 하는 거야?
second girl
두 번째 소녀
Miss, what are you doing?
아가씨, 뭐해요?
It's not a dream
꿈이 아니야
I really went back 2 years ago
정말 2년 전으로 돌아갔네요
I want to go back to see my mom and sister.
엄마랑 동생 보러 다시 가고 싶어요
Big lady ‥
큰 아가씨 ‥
Madam, you just got married.
부인, 방금 결혼하셨네요
Now how can I run to my parents' house?
이제 어떻게 부모님 집으로 달려갈 수 있나요?
If others find out, I might not know how to organize it.
남들이 알면 나도 어떻게 정리해야 할지 모를 수도 있다.
And your uncle will be here soon
그리고 삼촌이 곧 오실 거예요
- Madam - No, I want to see my mother.
- 부인 - 아니요, 어머니를 보고 싶어요
- Look at my dad and my brother. - It's really impossible...
- 우리 아빠랑 동생 좀 보세요 - 정말 불가능해요......
Big lady ‥
큰 아가씨 ‥
My uncle drank too much on the porch.
삼촌은 현관에서 술을 너무 많이 마셨다
I'm afraid I'll disturb you
당신을 방해할까 봐
Ask them to pass on the message.
메시지를 전달해 달라고 하세요.
I first rested in the study.
나는 먼저 서재에서 쉬었다.
i'm going out
내가 외출 해요
Uncle, during the day, the entire Mu family was arrested and imprisoned.
삼촌, 낮에는 무 가족 전체가 체포되어 투옥되었습니다.
Now the shepherd girl is a criminal wanted by the government.
이제 양치기 소녀는 정부가 수배하는 범죄자입니다
It's just that we used to be friendly.
그냥 우리가 예전에 친하게 지냈던 것뿐이야
It's better not to provoke him
그를 자극하지 않는 것이 좋습니다
I'll come back as soon as I go
가자마자 다시 올게
Uncle, today is your happy day.
삼촌, 오늘은 당신의 행복한 날입니다
The eldest lady is still waiting for you in the backyard room.
가장 큰 부인은 여전히 ​​뒷마당 방에서 당신을 기다리고 있습니다.
Just say you drank too much tonight
그냥 오늘 밤에 술을 너무 많이 마셨다고 하세요
sleeping in the lab
연구실에서 자고
So what should you do if she doesn't believe you?
그럼 그 여자가 믿지 않는다면 어떻게 해야 할까요?
Today is the wedding night of my uncle and his second daughter.
오늘은 삼촌과 둘째 딸의 결혼식 날 밤이다.
I want to go to the studio and take a look.
스터디 가서 한번 보고 싶네요
Was my uncle really drunk and unconscious?
삼촌은 정말 술에 취해 의식을 잃은 걸까요?
-Mr. Qianzhi... - Please get out of the way.
-치안즈 선생님 ‥ - 비켜주세요
Teacher Qianzhi, uncle went to bed
Qianzhi 선생님, 삼촌은 잠자리에 들었습니다
- Get out of the way, who are you kidding - Miss Qian Zhi
- 비켜라, 누구랑 장난하는 거야 - 미스 치안 지(Miss Qian Zhi)
Who are you kidding? I'll take a look. Get out of the way.
누구랑 장난하냐 내가 한번 살펴 볼게 비켜라
I saw the biggest lady
나는 가장 큰 부인을 보았다
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
Madam, please wait here.
부인, 여기서 기다리세요
I will go see my uncle right now and ask for an explanation.
지금 당장 삼촌을 찾아 가서 설명을 구하겠습니다.
Do not worry. I will definitely bring him back.
걱정하지 마세요. 제가 반드시 그 사람을 다시 데려올 거에요.
no need to go
갈 필요 없어
don't worry about this for now
지금은 이것에 대해 걱정하지 마십시오
Please go and prepare some bath water. I want to take a bath.
가서 목욕물 좀 준비해 주세요. 목욕하고 싶어요.
-But if my uncle comes later... -He won't come.
-근데 삼촌이 나중에 오시면...... -안 오실 거예요
How does the eldest lady know?
큰아줌마는 어떻게 알죠?
me
나
I just know
그냥 알아
oh my god
맙소사
you heard my prayer
내 기도를 들으셨네
So you gave it to me once.
그래서 한번 나한테 줬잖아
Is there a possibility of reform?
개편 가능성은?
-Please let me go -Please go‥
-가게 해주세요 -가세요 ‥
-Uncle ‥ -Hua Qian
-삼촌 ‥ -Hua Qian
At first you came to me pretending to be Mu Yao.
넌 처음에 무야오인 척 나한테 다가왔어
Then he secretly drugged me to force me to marry you.
그런 다음 그는 나에게 당신과 결혼하도록 강요하기 위해 비밀리에 나에게 약을 먹였습니다.
Finally with my father
마지막으로 아버지와 함께
Mu Yao's family was framed and imprisoned.
무야오의 가족을 모함하고 투옥함
Now the truth is revealed
이제 진실이 드러납니다
I can't hold you responsible for what you did
나는 당신이 한 일에 대해 책임을 물을 수 없습니다
It's just a clean break between you and me.
그것은 단지 당신과 나 사이의 깨끗한 휴식일 뿐입니다.
Not relevant
관련없음
uncle, don't kick me out
삼촌, 저를 쫓아내지 마세요
uncle‥
삼촌‥
don't kick me out
나를 쫓아내지 마세요
uncle
삼촌
The governor of the Zhong clan, Hwamun-nang, turned his back on his master and sought glory.
중씨 태수 화문낭(淮文惡)은 주인에게 등을 돌리고 영광을 구했다.
Maliciously framed and forcibly murdered his colleague Mu Yunping.
동료 무윤핑(Mu Yunping)을 악의적으로 모함하고 강제로 살해
Now sentenced to beheading
이제 참수형을 선고받음
The entire Hwa family was exiled to Yeongpyo.
화씨 가문은 모두 영표로 유배됨
Dare to help exiles escape
감히 망명자들의 탈출을 도우세요
20 sticks is considered a small amount of punishment.
막대기 20개는 적은 양의 처벌로 간주됩니다.
After all, he is still spoiled
결국, 그는 여전히 버릇이 없습니다
Thin skin and tender meat
얇은 껍질과 부드러운 고기
I didn't pass this either
이것도 통과하지 못했어
Why did you come back that day after worshiping at church?
왜 교회에서 예배를 드린 뒤 그날 로 돌아오셨나요 ?
Now is definitely not the time to confess that I did something wrong.
지금은 확실히 내가 뭔가 잘못했다고 고백할 때가 아닙니다 .
Otherwise, what is Jongye?
그렇지 않으면 종예란
He will definitely think that I am deliberately deceiving him.
그 사람은 내가 고의로 자기를 속이고 있다고 분명히 생각할 것이다.
First you have to hold something in your hand
먼저 손에 뭔가를 잡아야 해
furthermore
게다가
Mu Yunping was arrested and jailed yesterday.
어제 체포되어 투옥된 무윈핑
If I remember correctly
내가 기억하는 게 맞다면
Ten days after arrest
체포된 지 열흘 만에
He committed suicide in prison to prove his innocence.
그는 자신의 무죄를 증명하기 위해 감옥에서 자살했다.
This caused Mu Yaocai and the Hua family to fight to the death.
이로 인해 Mu Yaocai와 Hua 가족은 죽을 때까지 싸웠습니다.
It's too late to change now
지금 바꾸기엔 너무 늦었어
final death
최후의 죽음
It may not be fate
운명이 아닐 수도 있다
I can never go down the same path again
다시는 같은 길로 갈 수 없어
The same goes for the Fahrenheit family.
화씨 가족도 마찬가지다.
- Let's go - Lift your head up.
- 가자 - 너 고개를 들어
look carefully
주의 깊게 봐
Uncle, why are you here?
삼촌, 왜 여기 있어요?
I'll take people out to run errands.
심부름을 하러 사람들을 데리고 나가겠습니다
Please do whatever you want
마음대로 해주세요
Yes uncle, then you are busy first.
네, 삼촌 그럼 먼저 바쁘세요
The younger children will leave first.
어린아이들이 먼저 떠날 것이다.
Brother, let's go, follow us.
형제여, 가자 따라가라
let's go
갑시다
Wait, what's in the car?
잠깐, 차 안에 뭐가 있지?
firewood
장작
-Let's go . -Boss, who is this person?
-가자 -보스, 이 사람은 누구예요?
That person doesn't look like a high-ranking government official either.
그 사람도 고위공무원처럼 보이지는 않네요.
How did you meet him?
그 사람을 어떻게 만났어요?
Are you more nervous than ever about meeting your county magistrate?
우리 카운티 치안판사를 만나는 것보다 더 긴장되시나요?
Are you new from out of town?
타지에서 새로 왔나요?
The older brother who was just now the head of the head family.
방금 현재 종가의 당주였던 형
Even if it causes future displeasure to the county magistrates.
앞으로 카운티 치안 판사에게 불쾌감을 주더라도
We cannot offend anyone in his Zhong family.
우리는 그의 Zhong 가족 중 누구에게도 불쾌감을 줄 수 없습니다.
The mountains in our city are high, the emperor is far away, and the Zhong family has the final say.
우리 도시의 산은 높고 황제는 멀리 떨어져 있으며 종 가문이 최종 결정권을 가지고 있습니다.
Oh for what?
아 무엇 때문에?
The Zhong family controls all royal townships.
Zhong 가족은 모든 왕실 향을 통제합니다.
Even the holy one thousands of miles away
수천 리 떨어져 있는 거룩하신 분도
At first, I was willing to marry the eldest princess and the Zhong family.
처음에 나는 큰 공주와 종씨의 가족과 결혼할 의향이 있었습니다.
Taste it for yourself
직접 맛보세요
By the way, except for the Zhong family
그건 그렇고, 종 가족을 제외하고
The Hua family should also pay attention
Hua 가족도 주목해야합니다
- Be careful from now on and don't cause trouble to me. - Just a moment.
- 앞으로는 조심하시고 나한테 폐 끼치지 마세요 - 잠깐만요
Isn't the Hua family in charge of the Zhong family?
Hua 가족이 Zhong 가족을 담당하지 않습니까?
He doesn't just care about that.
그는 그것에 대해서만 신경 쓰지 않습니다.
He has the purchasing power of the Zhong family.
그는 Zhong 가문의 구매력을 보유하고 있습니다.
How much money does the Hua family make per year?
Hua 가족은 1년에 얼마나 많은 돈을 벌고 있나요?
More than county magistrates in 10 years
10년 만에 카운티 치안판사보다 많아
Excluding the city garden
종시 정원 제외
Are there any other houses in Huangshi that can compare to this?
황시에 이것과 비교할 수 있는 다른 집이 있습니까?
decent
괜찮은
The brothers followed closely behind.
형제들은 그 뒤를 바짝 따랐다.
walk
걷다
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
It's late, it's time to wake up
시간이 늦었어, 일어나야 할 시간이야
Today we go to Zhongshi Garden.
오늘은 중시 정원(Zhongshi Garden)으로 갑니다
go see the big princess
큰 공주를 만나러 가다
Didn’t the eldest lady sleep well?
큰아줌마는 잠을 잘 자지 않았나요?
not very good
별로 좋지 않아요
Then come back and wait until you can sleep.
그런 다음 돌아와서 잠을 잘 수 있을 때까지 기다리십시오.
What incense is burned in this incense burner?
이 향로에는 어떤 향이 태워지나요?
It's a bergamot scent that I use every day.
매일 사용하는 베르가못 향이에요
wrong
잘못된
Why do I feel it is different from bergamot?
왜 베르가못과 다르다고 느끼는 걸까요 ?
Do you have other perfumes?
다른 향수도 있나요?
No, there is only bergamot in this room.
아니요, 이 방에는 베르가못만 있어요
Did the big lady smell something different?
큰 아줌마에게서 다른 냄새가 났나요?
I can not say
말할 수 없다
Forget it, it might have been too long.
잊어버려, 너무 길었을지도 몰라
I even forgot the bergamot scent.
베르가못 향도 잊어버렸어요.
Madam, I'm worried that the housekeeper will be short-handed.
부인, 가사도우미가 일손이 부족할까봐 걱정이 되기 때문이죠.
It was specially delivered here early this morning.
오늘 이른 아침 이곳으로 특별히 배달되었습니다.
－Servant Cui Ju met the eldest daughter , and servant Ban Xia met the eldest daughter.
－하인 추이주는 장녀를 만났고 , 하인 반샤는 장녀를 만났습니다.
I went to Zhongshi Garden for the first time after my wedding.
결혼식 후 처음으로 중시 정원에 가봤습니다.
Madam, please dress more nicely.
부인, 좀 더 예쁘게 입으세요
Madam, you can change your clothes now.
부인, 이제 옷을 갈아입으시면 됩니다
Why is everyone white?
왜 다들 흰색이야?
Doesn’t the eldest lady always like white things?
큰아줌마는 항상 흰색만 좋아하는 거 아닌가요?
I gave you a special warning before
내가 전에도 특별히 경고했었지
Casual clothes after marriage
결혼 후 평상복
You still need to use white satin
여전히 흰색 새틴을 사용해야합니다
Plus, white makes people gentle.
게다가 흰색은 사람을 온화하게 만들어주죠
A match for the eldest sister’s beautiful face.
맏언니의 아름다운 얼굴에 걸맞은
Please help me order clothes of different colors on different days .
다른 날 다른 색상의 옷을 주문하도록 도와주세요 .
White is not stain resistant.
흰색은 얼룩에 강하지 않습니다.
I'm tired of wearing it too.
나도 입는 게 질렸어
It's time to get something new
새로운 것을 얻을 시간이다
yes ma'am
네, 부인
The slave saw his uncle
노예가 삼촌을 봤어
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
uncle
삼촌
I was so happy that I had a few more drinks last night.
너무 기뻐서 어젯밤에 술 몇 잔 더 마셨어
I slept in the study for fear of disturbing you.
나는 당신을 방해할까 봐 서재에서 잠을 잤습니다.
Will A Qian blame me?
A Qian이 나를 비난할까요?
I don't dare
나는 감히하지 않는다
You and I don't need to worry about this title.
당신과 나는 이 제목에 신경 쓸 필요가 없습니다.
Just call me like before
그냥 예전처럼 전화해
do
도
when you were fooled by me
네가 나한테 속았을 때
He was kind to me because he felt guilty
그는 죄책감을 느꼈기 때문에 나에게 친절했다
I was wrong once too
나도 한 번은 틀렸어
Paying such a big price
이렇게 큰 대가를 치르고
Don't make the same mistake this time
이번에는 같은 실수를 하지 마세요
When you see me like that, do you think you have something to say to me?
그런 나를 보면 혹시 나에게 할 말이라도 있는 걸까?
nothing more
더 아무것도
OK let's go
확인 가자
Now look at this
자, 이것 좀 보세요
Are you okay, boss?
괜찮으세요, 보스?
This is what you two want. You will be next.
이것이 너희 둘이 원하는 것이다. 다음은 너희가 될 것이다.
It's been a while since I've seen such a lively street scene.
이렇게 활기찬 거리 풍경을 본 것은 오랜만이다 .
But today I woke up early and haven’t even had breakfast yet.
그런데 오늘은 일찍 일어나서 아직 아침도 못 먹었어요.
Did your uncle eat it?
삼촌이 먹었어?
almost forgot
거의 잊었다
At this time he
그는 이때
I feel like my heart is full of Mu Yao, who saved me last night.
내 마음은 어젯밤에 구해준 무야오로 가득 차 있는 것 같아요 .
When Mu Yunping was last sentenced to life imprisonment
무윈핑이 마지막으로 종신형을 선고받았을 때
Mu Yao also escaped from the road where he was sold.
무야오도 팔려간 길에서 탈출했다.
Quick... go and search over there.
빨리......가서 저쪽으로 검색해 보세요
Don't let her escape.
그녀가 탈출하도록 놔두지 마세요
- Yes... - Wait a minute.
- 네 ‥ - 잠깐만요
let's go‥
갑시다‥
look carefully
주의 깊게 봐
are you okay
괜찮아요
Uncle, why are you here?
삼촌, 왜 여기 있어요?
I'll take people out to run errands.
심부름을 하러 사람들을 데리고 나가겠습니다
Please do whatever you want
마음대로 해주세요
Yes uncle, then you are busy first.
네, 삼촌 그럼 먼저 바쁘세요
The younger children will leave first.
어린아이들이 먼저 떠날 것이다.
Go and look over there and follow me.
가서 저쪽을 보고 따라오세요
follow me
날 따라와
Now the city is full of government officials catching fugitives.
이제 도시는 도망자를 잡는 정부 관리들로 가득 차 있습니다.
If you want to be taken away
빼앗기고 싶다면
You don't have to listen to me
내 말을 들을 필요는 없어
Now Mu Yao probably hates me in his heart.
이제 Mu Yao는 아마도 마음 속으로 나를 미워할 것입니다.
Of course you don't want to see me either
물론 너도 날 보고 싶지 않지
I never thought I'd have to do it again with a different feeling.
다른 기분으로 다시 해야 할 줄은 몰랐어요
In fact, it's harder than the reckless past.
사실은 무모했던 과거보다 더 힘들어
go away‥
저리 가요‥
steal my spot
내 자리를 훔쳐
- The garden is almost there - OK
- 종시 정원이 거의 다 왔습니다 - OK
It's a smelly place.
냄새나는 거지야
No snow when you walk?
걸을 때 눈이 없나요?
Did you say he was that young?
그렇게 어린 애라고 했죠?
I have hands and feet
손과 발이 있어
what's the problem
뭐가 문제 야
Why do we have to do this?
왜 이런 일을 해야 합니까?
What about that beggar that everyone despises?
모두가 경멸하는 그 거지는 어떻습니까?
I'm pretty good at reading people.
나는 사람을 읽는 데 꽤 능숙하다
I have really good eyes
눈이 참 좋은데
I know many wealthy families who lack slaves in their homes.
나는 집에 노예가 부족한 부유한 가족을 많이 알고 있습니다.
How about coming with me?
나와 함께 가는 게 어때?
Make sure you don't have to worry about eating and drinking
먹고 마시는 것에 대해 걱정할 필요가 없는지 확인하십시오
I’m also making some hard-earned money, right?
나도 힘들게 벌어서 돈 좀 벌고 있잖아?
how is it?
어때요?
Teacher Jang…
장 선생님…
- You stinky beggar - Get this kid out.
- 이 냄새나는 거지야 - 이 꼬마를 쫓아내라
Stop
멈추다
Where is my wallet?
내 지갑은 어디에 있나요?
This little bastard dares to steal from me
이 꼬마 새끼가 감히 내 물건을 훔치려 해
House owner
집주인
I met the head of the family
가장을 만났습니다
Brother, brother, are you here?
형님, 형님, 여기 계세요
Yesterday I wanted to go to Zhongzhai to congratulate you.
어제 나는 당신을 축하하기 위해 Zhongzhai에 가고 싶었습니다.
But my mother said she gave up because she was afraid I would disturb you.
하지만 어머니는 내가 당신을 방해할까 봐 두려워서 포기했다고 말씀하셨습니다.
The owner of the family missed it
가족의 주인이 그것을 놓쳤습니다
I've said it so many times
정말 여러번 말했지
You're still too polite to me.
아직도 나한테는 너무 예의바르잖아
you are my senior
당신은 내 선배예요
Just call me by my name
그냥 내 이름으로 불러줘
Still, there have to be rules
그래도 규칙은 있어야 해
I have something important to talk about with you later.
나중에 너랑 중요한 얘기할 게 있어
Let's go to mom's house together first.
먼저 엄마 집으로 같이 가자
good
좋은
It won't take long
오래 걸리지 않을 거예요
Even the head of the household will become a follower of Mu Yao.
가장조차도 무야오의 추종자가 될 것이다
It is natural that the Hua family's conspiracy was eventually revealed.
결국 화씨 가문의 음모가 밝혀진 것도 당연하다
You two, stop it.
너희 둘, 그만 좀 해라.
Which of us will you choose?
우리 중에 누구를 선택하시겠습니까 ‥
The rumor was huge at the time.
당시 소문이 엄청났는데
I still don't understand it.
나는 아직도 그것을 이해하지 못한다.
What is good about Muyao?
무야오의 좋은 점은 무엇인가요?
I can charm these two brothers to the point of killing them.
나는 이 두 형제를 죽일 정도로 매혹할 수 있다.
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
Madam, I just called you several times.
부인, 방금 몇 번이나 전화했어요
What do you think about?
당신은 무엇에 대한 생각?
It's no big deal, let's go quickly
별거 아니야 빨리 가자
What perfume are you using today?
오늘은 어떤 향수를 사용하시나요?
It smells like benzoin.
벤조인 냄새가 나네요
Meng is right.
멍씨 말이 맞아요
actually benzoin
실제로 벤조인
This scent has the effect of opening the mind and calming the blood.
이 향은 마음을 열고 혈액을 진정시키는 효과가 있습니다.
May prevent heart and stomach pain
심장과 위의 통증을 예방할 수 있습니다
Laner comes here only once.
랜어는 여기 딱 한 번만 와요
Let's switch to sandalwood, which he likes.
그가 좋아하는 백단향으로 바꾸자.
Yes, princess
응, 공주님
The eldest princess is really kind to her uncle.
큰 공주는 삼촌에게 정말 친절합니다.
The child saw his mother
아이가 엄마를 봤어요
- The child met the big princess - I met the big princess
- 아이가 큰 공주를 만났어요 - 나는 큰 공주를 만났어요
Please sit down quickly
빨리 앉으세요
mother
어머니
language
랜어
In the blink of an eye you'll be married
눈 깜짝할 사이에 당신은 결혼을 하게 됩니다
you choose your wife yourself
당신은 당신의 아내를 스스로 선택합니다
Let's get along well in the future
앞으로도 잘 지내자
Remember the teachings of the Big Princess
큰 공주의 가르침을 기억하십시오
First, the head of the household accepted you as a closed disciple.
첫째, 가장이 당신을 닫힌 제자로 받아들였습니다.
You too have grown up in this garden since you were a child.
당신도 어렸을 때부터 이 정원에서 자랐어요.
Why do we have to divide it like this?
왜 이렇게 나누어야 합니까?
Don't you want to call me 'master's wife'?
나를 '주인님의 아내'라고 부르고 싶지 않으세요?
Yes, mistress.
응, 여주인
how about you
당신은요
Since you married Zhongzhai as you wished,
당신이 원하는 대로 중자이에게 시집을 갔으니,
Be careful in the future
앞으로는 조심하세요
Be a good wife to Zhongzhai
Zhongzhai의 좋은 아내가 되십시오
Take it easy and pamper yourself.
진정하고 자신을 가꾸세요.
Frugality fosters virtue
검소함은 덕을 키운다
Remember not to do anything dishonorable again
다시는 불명예스러운 일을 하지 않도록 기억하십시오
Why do I hear this?
왜 이런 말을 듣나요?
I think the big princess knows too
큰 공주도 알고 있는 것 같아
The fact that Jong Ye-ran married me
종예란이 나와 결혼했다는 사실
Isn't this matter extremely secret?
이 문제는 극히 비밀이 아닌가?
Teachings of the Big Princess
큰 공주의 가르침
I keep this in mind
나는 이것을 명심한다
It's no use remembering it in words
말로 기억해봤자 소용없어
just do it
그냥 해
The identity of the concubine will be determined later.
첩의 신원은 추후 결정될 예정
Be consistent in your words and actions, exercise restraint, and return to manners.
말과 행동이 일관되고 자제하며 예절로 돌아가라
good
좋은
Then I'll watch.
그럼 지켜볼게
I will never disappoint you
나는 결코 당신을 실망시키지 않을 것입니다
The big princess is full of teaching emotions.
큰 공주는 가르치는 감정으로 가득 차 있습니다.
Because you want to save your life
당신은 목숨을 구하고 싶기 때문에
The first step is to replace the image
첫 번째 단계는 이미지를 바꾸는 것입니다
mother
어머니
My brother and I still have important things to discuss.
형과 나는 아직 중요한 의논할 일이 남아 있다.
- Now I'll say goodbye. - Okay.
- 이제 작별인사를 할게요 - 알았어
You go and do your work first.
너 먼저 가서 일이나 해
Yesterday, Manager Meng sent another shipment from the south.
어제 맹 과장이 남쪽에서 또 다른 화물을 보냈습니다.
It contains unique cedar seeds and facial butter.
거기에 독특한 삼나무씨앗과 페이셜 버터가 들어있어요
You can choose one later.
나중에 하나를 선택할 수 있습니다.
See what you like.
당신이 좋아하는 것을 보아라.
Thank you so much, princess.
정말 고마워요, 공주님.
Thank you for your kindness, big princess.
큰 공주님의 친절에 감사드립니다.
But it was given to the older princess by her father.
하지만 그것은 아버지가 큰 공주에게 준 것입니다.
How dare I ask for that?
내가 어떻게 감히 그것을 요구합니까?
Your father worked alone in the south for the Zhong family.
당신의 아버지는 Zhong 가족을 위해 남쪽에서 혼자 일했습니다.
You have been with me in this garden for many years.
당신은 이 정원에서 나와 함께 오랜 세월 동안 함께 해왔습니다.
This little thing is nothing
이 작은 것은 아무것도 아니다
how about you
당신은요
Your father took over the Northern store last year.
작년에 당신 아버지가 북부 상점을 인수하셨는데요
Thank you for your hard work too.
노고에도 감사드립니다
What's so difficult about this?
이게 뭐가 그렇게 어렵나요?
That's what daddy should do
그게 아빠가 해야 할 일이야
It is said that the eldest princess reads Buddhist scriptures every day.
큰 공주는 매일 불경을 읽는다고 한다
I saw Sister Chi a while ago.
얼마 전에 치 자매님을 봤어요
Several volumes of Buddhist scriptures were newly copied.
여러 권의 불교 경전을 새로 필사했습니다.
Are you thinking of giving it to your big princess?
큰 공주님께 줄 생각이신가요?
Sister Meng has very sharp eyes.
맹 자매는 눈이 매우 예리합니다
That's what I'll give the big princess
그게 내가 큰 공주에게 줄 거야
I'll send it to you another day.
다른 날에 보내드릴게요
It's rare to be this young.
이렇게 어린 경우는 드물다
Then just calm down and copy the Buddhist scriptures.
그러면 진정하고 불경을 베껴 쓰시면 됩니다
It's better to be quiet than hasty
성급한 것보다 조용한 것이 낫다
you look like this
당신은 이렇게 생겼어요
Are you dissatisfied with something I said?
내가 한 말에 불만이 있나요?
As a woman, I ask this.
여자로서 묻겠습니다.
What are your priorities?
우선 순위는 무엇입니까?
Princess Hui
후이공주
As the ancients said, women have four virtues:
고대인들이 말했듯이 여성에게는 네 가지 미덕이 있습니다.
Virtue, appearance, words, merit
덕, 용모, 말, 공덕
good
좋은
You know virtue comes first
당신도 미덕이 먼저라는 걸 알고 있죠
From now on, you need to take good care of yourself and your family.
앞으로는 자신과 가족을 잘 가꾸어야 합니다.
Please be a good helper by Lanier’s side.
랜이어의 옆에서 좋은 조력자가 되어주세요
I will definitely keep the eldest princess’s teachings in mind.
큰공주님의 가르침을 꼭 명심하겠습니다
Yesterday I heard that there was a new goldfish in the backyard pond.
어제 뒷마당 연못에 새로운 금붕어가 생겼다 는 소식을 들었습니다 .
Princess, would you like to go and take a look now?
공주님, 지금 가서 살펴보실래요?
great
좋아요
go out for a walk
산책하러 나가다
Why don't you follow me?
왜 따라오지 않니?
yes
예
The first step of changing the image still seems useful.
이미지를 바꾸는 첫 번째 단계는 여전히 유용한 것 같습니다.
At least the big princess is not the same as her previous life
적어도 큰 공주는 전생과 같지 않습니다
leave me alone at home
나를 집에 혼자 남겨두세요
Look at that
저거 좀 봐
Princess, take a look quickly.
공주님, 빨리 보세요
They had so much fun catching it
그들은 그것을 잡는 것이 너무 재미있었습니다
come
오다
big princess
큰 공주
Look at that person swimming over there.
저기 수영하는 저 사람 좀 보세요.
There are several things here
여기에는 여러 가지가 있습니다
Everyone is busy trying to eat this.
다들 이거 먹으려고 분주하네요.
- Look - Last Life
-보세요 -마지막 인생
I didn't have much contact with the Zhong Garden people.
나는 종씨 정원 사람들과 별로 접촉을 하지 않았습니다.
I didn't know there was a woman in this large garden.
이 넓은 정원에 여자가 있을줄은 몰랐어
Life was so boring too
인생도 너무 지루했어요
I just saw some goldfish
방금 금붕어 몇 마리를 봤어요
But can you be this happy?
하지만 이렇게나 행복할 수 있니
I really ate it
정말 먹었어요
-These two colors are really unique.
-이 두 가지 색상이 정말 독특 해요.
Those two look good too
그 둘도 좋아 보여요
-Yes - Look
-네 -보세요
Everyone is holding it over there.
다들 저기서 잡고 있어
Look at
바라보다
See you quickly
빨리 봐
- Small fish are really edible. - Yes.
- 작은 물고기는 정말 먹을 수 있어요 - 그렇죠
Big lady ‥
큰 아가씨 ‥
Lady Jungda's clothes
중다부인의 옷
-Someone come quickly -Someone help me quickly
-누가 빨리 와요 -누가 빨리 도와주세요
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
What should I do about this problem?
이 문제에 대해 어떻게 해야 합니까?
Big lady ‥
큰 아가씨 ‥
Come on, slow down.
자, 속도를 줄여요
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
When did you learn to swim?
언제 수영하는 법을 배웠나요?
1 year in exile
망명 1년
What else can't you learn?
또 무엇을 배울 수 없습니까?
Big lady ‥
큰 아가씨 ‥
Come down quickly and clean up.
빨리 내려가서 청소하세요.
-Miss -let 's go
-아가씨 -가자
How could Mrs. Hah do this...
화씨 부인이 어떻게 이럴 수가 ......
How did she fall into the water?
그녀는 어떻게 물에 빠졌나요?
This is Yuju, a low-class maid who approaches Hwaman on weekdays .
평일에 화만의 곁에 다가가는 하급 하녀 유주 입니다.
Brother, look
형님, 보세요
This is the case where Mu Yunping committed suicide under supervision.
무윤핑이 감독하에 자살한 사건은 이렇습니다.
Counterfeit Agarwood Pills Returned by a Regular Customer
단골 고객이 반품한 위조 침향 알약
I took the exam for two days.
이틀동안 시험을 봤는데
Only then did we find out how the agarwood powder had been counterfeited.
그제야 우리는 침향 가루가 어떻게 위조되었는지 알아냈습니다.
It seems quite similar to the Ge family's methods.
Ge 가문의 방식과 상당히 유사한 것 같습니다.
family?
가족?
how?
어떻게요?
My brother worked alone.
형은 혼자 일했다.
Reveals an incident in which the Ge family secretly used incense to harm people.
게씨 일가가 몰래 향을 사용해 사람들에게 해를 끼친 사건을 폭로하다
So you must know their methods
그래서 당신은 그들의 방법을 알고 있어야합니다
If you don't believe me, you can try it.
믿기지 않는다면 시도해 볼 수 있습니다.
I have already mentioned a few things to Judge Wang Hyeon in confidence.
나는 이미 왕현판사에게 비밀리에 몇 가지 사항을 언급했습니다.
But he hasn't found any clues yet.
하지만 그는 아직 단서를 찾지 못했습니다.
Almost 10 years have passed since the Ge family was confiscated by the government .
Ge 가족이 정부에 의해 몰수된 지 거의 10년이 지났습니다 .
Even though there were a few fish that slipped through the net at that time,
그 당시에는 그물 사이로 빠져나간 물고기가 몇 마리 있었다고 해도
I'm worried that it won't be easy to get ahead now.
이제는 쉽게 앞서가기가 어려울 것 같아 걱정입니다.
Moreover, this Mu Yunping
게다가 이 무윤핑(Mu Yunping)
Less than a year has passed since I was transported from the north to Huangcheng.
내가 북쪽에서 황성(黃成)으로 이송된 지 채 1년이 되지 않았습니다.
It shouldn't be relevant. Yes?
그것은 관련되어서는 안 됩니다. 그렇죠?
hard to say
말하기 어렵다
Perhaps the Ge family has been recovering in secret for many years.
아마도 Ge 가족은 수년 동안 비밀리에 회복해 왔을 것입니다.
Now ready for a comeback
이제 컴백 준비 완료
Now I am worried that the Zhong family has infiltrated them.
이제는 종씨 일가가 그들에게 침투한 것 같아 걱정스럽기도 합니다.
Magistrate Wang sentenced Mu Yunping to exile to Lingbiao.
왕 치안판사는 무윈핑(Mu Yunping)에게 영표(Lingbiao)로 망명하라는 선고를 내렸습니다.
There was only one person in the Mu family who had to sell and receive compensation.
뮤 가문에서 팔아 보상을 받아야 할 사람은 단 한 명뿐이었다 .
still missing
아직도 행방불명
They searched the entire city but found nothing.
도시 전체를 수색했지만 아무것도 발견하지 못했습니다.
I don't know if this is the Ge family's work.
이것이 Ge 가족의 작품인지 모르겠습니다.
uncle
삼촌
Madam Hua, she
화 부인, 그녀는
she accidentally fell into the water
그녀는 실수로 물에 빠졌다
what?
무엇?
What happen?
무슨 일이에요?
Just now, Master, Big Princess and Madame Fahrenheit.
방금 스승님, 큰 공주님과 화씨 부인
Watching fish together in the backyard
뒷뜰에서 함께 물고기 구경하기
I don't know why
왜인지 모르겠어요
Mrs. Hah fell into the pond.
화씨 부인이 연못에 빠졌어요
But it's no big deal
하지만 별거 아니야
Madam Hua, she
화 부인, 그녀는
she swam on her own
그녀는 스스로 수영했어요
- Go down first - Yes.
- 먼저 내려가세요 - 예
Check with Chen Yuan.
Chen Yuan에게 확인해 보세요.
Yes, he is the head of the family.
응, 가장이야
magistrate
치안 지
My sister finally got what she wanted
내 여동생이 마침내 원하는 것을 얻었어
Became the eldest daughter of the Zhong family.
중씨 가문의 장녀가 됨
i am your sister
나는 여동생이다
I'm so happy for you
당신이 있어서 정말 기뻐요
Miss Man is like this
미스맨은 이렇게
How to Stand Behind and Celebrate Quietly
뒤에 서서 조용히 축하하는 방법
It's really shocking.
정말 충격적이네요.
Why is my sister so unfamiliar today?
오늘 우리 누나는 왜 이렇게 낯설지?
You and I can be considered blood relatives.
당신과 나는 혈족으로 간주될 수 있습니다.
I used to talk about everything
난 모든 것에 대해 이야기하곤 했어
it turns out
그것은 밝혀
I have been working with my old boss for over 10 years.
나는 옛 상사와 10년 넘게 함께 일해 왔습니다.
If you want to go to the Central Garden
중시 정원에 가고 싶다면
The current head of the household will give you the position of eldest daughter if you don't talk much.
현재 가장은 말을 많이 하지 않으면 장녀 자리를 줄 것입니다 .
- how is it? -Dad now belongs to the Zhong family and is in charge.
- 어때요? -아빠는 이제 Zhong 가족에 속해 있으며 책임자입니다.
Do you still need me to please the matriarch and the eldest princess?
가장과 큰 공주를 기쁘게하려면 아직도 내가 필요합니까?
Besides, it’s not like Dad doesn’t know.
게다가 아빠가 모르는 것도 아니고
The only person I want to marry is my uncle.
내가 결혼하고 싶은 유일한 사람은 나의 삼촌이다.
That's it
그게 다야
Who told me to keep you as my daughter?
누가 나한테 너만 내 딸로 두라고 했어?
Because you don't want to go
네가 가고 싶지 않으니까
I'll send you your uncle's eldest daughter.
네 삼촌의 큰 딸을 보내줄게
After all, in the garden of bells
결국, 종의 정원에서
There must be someone named Hua.
Hua라는 사람이 있을 거에요.
consanguinity
혈족
What's wrong with my sister?
내 여동생에게 무슨 문제가 있는 걸까요?
Miss Man is now the first-class handmaid of the head of the household.
Miss Man은 이제 가장의 일급 여종입니다.
From now on, don't hang out with your sisters.
앞으로는 언니들과 어울리지 마세요.
I can't stand my sister's noises
누나의 소리를 참을 수가 없어
i made a mistake
제가 실수를
I haven't seen my eldest aunt for a long time.
나는 큰 아줌마를 오랫동안 보지 못했습니다.
It took a lot of effort to prepare for the meeting.
회의를 준비하는 데 많은 노력이 필요했습니다.
We became friends for a while and then I made a mistake.
잠시 친해지다 말실수를 하기도 했습니다.
prepare?
마련하다?
The eldest lady is surrounded by too many people.
큰아줌마는 너무 많은 사람들에게 둘러싸여 있다
The big princess is thinking of you again
큰 공주가 또 당신을 생각하고 있어요
I would like to speak to you personally.
당신에게 개인적인 말을 하고 싶습니다.
this is a last resort
이것은 최후의 수단이다
So I made this decision
그래서 이런 결정을 하게 됐어요
The person who just pushed me into the water.
방금 나를 물에 밀어넣은 사람
It was you who organized it.
정리한 건 너였어
There is already a mother familiar with the water waiting at the water's edge.
물가에서 기다리고 있는 물에 익숙한 어머니가 이미 계십니다.
I won't let my eldest lady get hurt.
큰아줌마가 상처받게 놔두지 않을 거예요.
Besides, there are a lot of spies in this garden.
게다가 이 정원에는 스파이들이 많이 있어요.
This is the only way to avoid arousing suspicion.
이것이 의심을 불러일으키는 것을 피할 수 있는 유일한 방법입니다.
Why didn't that happen in the past?
과거에는 왜 그런 일이 일어나지 않았나요?
correct
옳은
In the past, the eldest princess deliberately left it in her room.
과거에는 큰 공주님이 일부러 방에 남겨 두었습니다 .
Look at
바라보다
So bold.
정말 대담하다
Do you really think Zhong's Garden belongs to the Hua family?
정말로 Zhong's Garden이 Hua 가족의 소유라고 생각하시나요?
miss you
보고싶다
It's right under my nose
내 코 바로 밑에 있어
What message can you convey?
어떤 메시지를 전달할 수 있나요?
Miss Man is so thoughtful.
Miss Man은 너무 사려 깊습니다.
If you have something to say, you can say it directly.
하고 싶은 말이 있으면 직접 말해도 됩니다.
Why are you so secretive?
왜 그렇게 비밀스러워?
There are many eyes and ears in this garden
이 정원에는 많은 눈과 귀가 있습니다
a few
몇 가지
I still have to bother my eldest aunt to deliver it.
아직도 그것을 배달하려면 큰아줌마를 귀찮게 해야 합니다.
Mu Yunping was imprisoned.
무윤핑은 감옥에 갇혔다.
Now there's no turning back
이제 돌이킬 날이 없구나
－Please ask the flower master‥ － This is ridiculous.
－화도에게 부탁해 보시기 바랍니다‥ － 어이없네요
Have you lost your mind?
정신을 잃었나요?
master's business
주인의 사업
How could you, a female envoy, dare make such arrogant remarks?
여자 사절인 당신이 어찌 감히 그런 오만한 발언을 할 수 있겠습니까?
Why should my father know?
왜 아버지가 알아야 합니까?
What's going on at home?
집에서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있나요?
I've already taken care of everything here.
나는 이미 여기서 모든 것을 처리했습니다.
No one will notice
아무도 눈치채지 못할 거야
Madam, you can rest assured.
부인 안심하셔도 됩니다
It is natural that the Hah family collapsed in the past life.
화씨 가문이 전생에 무너진 것도 당연지사
Everyone is so stupid and has such a bad personality.
다들 이런 멍청하고 나쁜 성격이구나
I don't understand what Miss Man is saying.
저는 Miss Man이 무슨 말을 하는지 이해하지 못합니다.
Do you have something to secretly say?
혹시 몰래 할 말이라도 있나요?
Madam, you are really forgetful.
부인, 정말 건망증이 많으세요
At first, Hwadugwan sent me to the servant's garden to raise me more.
처음에 화두관은 나를 종의 정원으로 보내어 나를 더 많이 길러 주었습니다.
Am I not the only one staying here?
나만 여기에 머무르는 것이 아닌가?
Can you help him?
그를 도와줄 수 있나요?
Miss Man Are you really confused?
미스맨 정말 혼란스럽나요?
You are the one who wants to enter the Garden of Species.
종의 정원에 들어가고 싶은 사람은 바로 당신입니다.
Because my uncle's status is too low to do anything.
삼촌의 지위가 너무 낮아서 아무것도 할 수 없으니까
father misses brotherhood
아버지는 형제애를 그리워한다
Talent and a helping hand
재능과 도움의 손길
Why have you become head of my father’s house?
어찌하여 당신이 내 아버지 집의 우두머리가 되었나이까?
Because you are my cousin
당신은 내 사촌이니까
I won't tell anyone what happened today
오늘 무슨 일이 있었는지 아무에게도 말하지 않을 거예요
I will never track you again
다시는 추적하지 않겠습니다
Just for today
오늘만
I wish Miss Man would stop pulling pranks like that.
Miss Man이 그런 장난을 그만 쳤으면 좋겠어요.
hurt feelings in the past
과거의 감정을 상하게 하다
Is the eldest lady in a daze today?
오늘 큰아줌마는 멍해있나요?
Did you actually say that?
실제로 그런 말을 했죠?
If you weren't so obsessed with the Zhong family,
당신이 종 씨 가족에 그렇게 집착하지 않았다면,
How could Hua Du Guan send me to Zhongshi Garden?
Hua Du Guan은 어떻게 나를 Zhongshi Garden으로 보낼 수 있습니까?
Do you make way for him?
그를 위해 길을 열어주나요?
What Miss Man Said
미스맨이 한 말
It hurts so much
너무 아프다
I am truly loyal to my uncle.
나는 삼촌에게 진심으로 충성한다
But if it's my father
하지만 그게 아버지라면
I would like to staff this garden.
이 종시 정원에 인력을 배치하고 싶습니다
There are so many beautiful women in the Fahrenheit clan.
화씨족에는 아름다운 여성이 너무 많습니다
Why should your father choose you?
왜 아버지가 당신을 선택해야 합니까?
I said it myself
직접 말했잖아
I fell in love with my master
나는 주인님에게 반했어요
My father said that because of the brotherly love between uncles,
아버지는 삼촌간의 형제애 때문에
We've made an exception to help you.
도움을 드리고자 예외를 두었습니다
Have pity on your kindness
아버지의 친절하심을 불쌍히 여기소서
But I was misunderstood
그런데 오해를 받았어요
How dare you call me ugly?
감히 나를 못생겼다고 할 수 있어?
You get the point well.
핵심을 잘 파악하시는군요.
Anyway, I'll tell my father later.
어쨌든 나중에 아버지께 말씀드릴게.
Quit it for brotherhood.
형제애 때문에 그만둬라
And repeatedly create exceptions
그리고 반복적으로 예외를 만들어요
Because I'm obsessed with the landlord
집주인에게 집착하니까
Then don't put your thoughts anywhere else.
그런 다음 다른 곳에 생각을 두지 마십시오.
The principle of one servant serving two masters
한 종이 두 주인을 섬기는 원칙
You don’t need me to teach you any more, right?
더 이상 내가 가르쳐 줄 필요가 없잖아요?
you‥
너‥
Hello, Hua Chen.
안녕하세요 화첸님
He really turned his back on me and didn't recognize anyone.
그는 정말로 나에게 등을 돌리고 누구도 알아보지 못했습니다.
She's just a big woman who gained power by drugging herself.
그녀는 단지 자신에게 약을 먹여서 권력을 잡은 큰 여자 일 뿐입니다 .
You still have the courage to pretend to be righteous in front of me.
넌 아직도 내 앞에서 정의로운 척 할 용기가 있구나
oldest woman
가장 나이 많은 여자
Madam, why are you coming out with messy hair?
부인, 왜 헝클어진 머리로 나오시나요?
When I saw that no one was home, I came out to look for you.
집에 아무도 없는 것을 보고 당신을 찾으러 나왔습니다.
The maid just told me to clean up.
방금 가정부가 나에게 청소를 하라고 했어요
The eldest lady changed into her wet clothes.
큰아줌마는 젖은 옷으로 갈아입었습니다.
Madam, go comb your hair first.
부인, 먼저 머리를 빗으러 가세요.
Don't they always like it?
그들은 항상 그것을 좋아하지 않습니까?
Do you act like sisters to the outside world?
당신은 외부 세계와 자매처럼 행동합니까?
Do you think Hua Qian knows we are here?
Hua Qian이 우리가 여기 있다는 것을 알고 있다고 생각하시나요 ?
I don't know, kid.
모르겠어요, 꼬마야
I heard you're going to your brother's house tomorrow.
내일 형 집에 간다고 들었어.
When my brother welcomes you tomorrow, I have nothing to do.
내일 형이 당신을 맞이하면 나는 할 일이 없습니다.
I just wanted to join in on the fun.
난 그냥 그 재미에 동참하고 싶었을 뿐이야
you two brothers
너희 두 형제
It doesn't matter when we meet
언제 만나든 상관없어
don't go there tomorrow
내일은 거기 가지 마세요
Is your mother dissatisfied with Fahrenheit's daughter?
당신의 어머니는 화씨의 딸에 대해 불만이 있습니까?
I don't like it a little bit
조금 마음에 안 드는데
I have seen too many ways to exploit people's weaknesses to win their hearts.
나는 사람들의 마음을 얻기 위해 약점을 이용하는 수법을 너무 많이 보았습니다.
Plus a Chinese woman
게다가 중국여자
She also used immoral methods to get married.
그녀는 또한 결혼하기 위해 부도덕한 방법을 사용했습니다.
A housewife must be steady and calm.
주부는 꾸준하고 침착해야 합니다.
When times are difficult, we cry and seek sympathy from others.
어려울 때 울고 울며 다른 사람의 동정을 구합니다.
That's what concubines do.
첩이 하는 짓이야
That's Lan'er's truth.
그게 란어의 진심이군요
Decided to take responsibility for your own reputation
자신의 평판에 대해 책임을 지기로 결심함
Don't listen to what others say.
남의 말을 듣지 마세요.
Brother, you are still kind.
형님은 아직도 착하시네요
you are the head of the family
당신은 가족의 가장입니다
It's different from Raynor.
레이너와는 다르다
Don't be weak-hearted from now on.
앞으로는 마음 약하게 굴지 마
Don't be fooled by these little tricks
이런 작은 속임수에 속지 마세요
mother
어머니
Daily life is already busy enough.
일상적인 일은 이미 충분히 바쁘다.
How can a child put his mind elsewhere?
아이가 어떻게 마음을 다른 곳에 둘 수 있겠습니까?
I just know
그냥 알아
continued
계속되는
Thanks for watching
시청 해주셔서 감사합니다